Let's talk now about how to select a jig rod.
There's many different varieties out there.
They all come down, at their most basic, to having a handle and a reel seat, so you can attach your reel to it.
Then simply, the more sensitive end of the rod, along with rod eyelets.
You can buy these jig rods.
It's a combination that come with both the rod and the reel or you can buy the rod and the reel separately.
Ultimately, what you want to do is match the size rod and the action of the rod, to the fish species that you're fishing for.
For example, if I were fishing for lake trout or bass or larger fish, such as that, I would want a rod that wasn't very flexible.
I would want one even stiffer than this, that didn't have this give, because when you need to set that hook on a bigger fish or at greater depths, you want stoutness of that rod to work in your advantage.
However, when you're fishing for perch or sunfish, you want a rod with lighter action that bends, almost at the drop of a hat.
It's very sensitive because the pan fish are very light biters so you want a sensitive rod tip, to feel that bite and also to cushion that fish as it comes up.
Typically, with pan fish, you're fishing with very light line, maybe two or four pound test monofilament.
That rod, again, is working to your advantage.